<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>docs.plakar.io</title><link>https://docs.plakar.io/en/index.html</link><description>What’s plakar ? plakar is a free and opensource utility to create distributed, versioned backups with compression, encryption and data deduplication.
With a very clear goal to simplify backups, it is designed to be straightforward to use. It requires a few seconds to install and only a few minutes to get backups set up and running: creating a backup is as simple as typing plakar backup and restoring as simple as typing plakar restore.</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 21:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://docs.plakar.io/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Quick start</title><link>https://docs.plakar.io/en/quickstart/index.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 21:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://docs.plakar.io/en/quickstart/index.html</guid><description>This article will guide you through the creation of your first backup with plakar.
Installing plakar The first step is to install the software.
At the time of this writing, we do not yet provide packages and plakar has to be installed manually:
$ go install https://github.com/PlakarKorp/plakar@latest This will ensure that dependencies are installed and you should be able to verify the command is properly installed:
$ plakar version v0.4.27-alpha $ Running the local agent To work efficiently, plakar requires each user to run a local agent that will provide caching among other things. If the agent is not running, the plakar CLI will operate in degraded mode as a safety net, but will disallow concurrent commands and won’t benefit from caching.</description></item><item><title>Concepts</title><link>https://docs.plakar.io/en/concepts/index.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2022 23:27:47 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://docs.plakar.io/en/concepts/index.html</guid><description>Concepts This page documents in a very simplified way the concepts used by plakar.
Repositories At the core of plakar are repositories.
A repository is a storage unit within which backups are stored. You can have one or many different repositories, some encrypted and others not, each backed by your local filesystem, a database or even a remote server.
They should be considered as locations, rather than directories: you point the utility there so it can store snapshots or retrieve data from snapshots.</description></item><item><title>Commands</title><link>https://docs.plakar.io/en/commands/index.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2022 23:27:47 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://docs.plakar.io/en/commands/index.html</guid><description>Documented commands Plakar</description></item><item><title>Community</title><link>https://docs.plakar.io/en/community/index.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2022 23:27:47 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://docs.plakar.io/en/community/index.html</guid><description>Join the Plakar community ! As Plakar evolves into both a Community Edition (free and open-source) and Enterprise Edition (with additional features and commercial support), we invite everyone to join our growing community.
Connect with developers, users, and contributors in real time, share feedback, and stay updated on the latest features.
Whether you’re using the Community or Enterprise Edition, everyone is welcome!
Join our Discord server here!</description></item></channel></rss>