<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Quickstart - docs.plakar.io</title><link>https://docs.plakar.io/en/quickstart/index.html</link><description>This article will guide you through the creation of your first backup with plakar.
Installing plakar Requisites At the time of this writing, we do not yet provide packages and plakar has to be compiled from source, which requires the Go toolchain to be installed on your system.
To install the Go toolchain, please refer to the official documentation or run the following commands:</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 17:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://docs.plakar.io/en/quickstart/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>One repository is not enough</title><link>https://docs.plakar.io/en/quickstart/probabilities/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 17:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://docs.plakar.io/en/quickstart/probabilities/index.html</guid><description>Plakar offers a simple way to synchronize repositories across multiple locations. Two questions often arise: “Why do I need more than one copy?” and “How many copies should I have?”
Why do I need more than one copy? If you store your data at a single location, you are at risk of losing everything if that storage fails. This can happen due to various reasons, such as:
Hardware failure: The device’s components can fail due to wear and tear, overheating, or other issues. Power surges: Unexpected power surges can damage the device and corrupt the data. Natural disasters: Fires, floods, earthquakes, or other natural disasters can destroy the device and the data stored on it. Theft: The device can be stolen, and the data can be lost or compromised. Hardware failures are not the only risk to your data. Human errors can also lead to data loss. Some common scenarios include:</description></item></channel></rss>